Lucas Rosinelli da Rocha

Lisbon, Portugal

+351 965 507 579 | contact@lucasrosinelli.com | LinkedIn | Website

Career Summary

In a nutshell: I transform an idea into software. Software developer with over 15 years of experience. Driven by high-quality standards, I deliver software solutions to increase processes automation, effectiveness and efficiency on web, desktop, and mobile devices. Bachelor's degree in Computer Science.

Work Experience

Apr 2020 – Present Lisbon, Portugal

Tech Lead | INSCALE

Duties

Duties

- Mentoring and technical leadership to a team of developers
- Develop software solutions, new user interfaces, software tools and other applications
- Review functional specifications and participate in the development of creative ideas for functionality and user interface
- Create technical design, technical specifications, documentation of developed code
- Hiring additional personnel
- Client served as 3rd party: Signicat

Stacks, Tools, Software and more: C#, .NET 5, .NET Core 3.1, MongoDB, xUnit, Moq, ASP.NET Web API, REST, ASP.NET MVC, Swagger, OAuth 2.0, OIDC, Redis, Angular 10, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, gRPC, GitLab with CI/CD pipelines, Snyk, SonarCloud, AWS, Azure, Prometheus, Kibana, Grafana, Clean Architecture, Agile, Scrum, XP, SDLC, Jira, Confluence

Mar 2019 – Apr 2020 Lisbon, Portugal

Software engineer | Vision-box

ortware engineer | vision-bo

- Configure new and existing functionalities for Automated Border Control
- Troubleshooting acceptance and production environments behaviours
- Assure system correctness testing different devices and projects, according to system specifications and client needs
- Maintain test scripts updated based on most recent documentation approved
- Perform all tests required in different environments (Development, SQA, Acceptance and Production) and create specific and detailed reports
- Hiring additional personnel

Achievements

- Elaborate and present technical documentation to clients (Dutch Ministry of Justice and Security & Amsterdam Airport Schiphol)
- Create structured documentation for existing processes in the team Stacks, Tools, Software and more: C#, .NET Framework (4.6+), .NET Core (2.0 and 3.1), SQL Server, Entity Framework, xUnit, Moq, ASP.NET Web API, REST, Swagger, Angular, React, Jenkins, Kibana, Grafana, Agile, Scrum, SDLC, Jira, Confluence

Sep 2012 – Mar 2019 São Paulo/SP, Brazil

Full Stack Developer | NEXXYS

- Create technical design, technical specifications, documentation of developed code
- Develop software solutions, new user interfaces, software tools and other applications
- Review functional specifications and participate in the development of creative ideas for functionality and user interface
- Research and development of proof of concepts and prototypes for new business opportunities and product's improvements
- Mentoring and technical leadership to a team of developers
- Hiring additional personnel

Achievements

- Improvements, performance, and refactoring implemented, focusing on coding readability and maintenance, scalability, and reusability
- Increased the company's revenue by introducing a new idea in real-time data delivery solution for our clients through a dashboard using SignalR and a mobile app

Stacks, Tools, Softwares and more: C#, .NET Framework (2.0, 3.5, 4.5 and 4.6), SQL Server, MongoDB, MySQL, Dapper, Entity Framework, xUnit, Moq, Swagger, ASP.NET Web API, REST, ASP.NET MVC, SignalR, ASP.NET Web Forms, Windows Forms, Windows Services, WCF, Silverlight, Angular, React, Ionic, React Native, DDD, Git, AWS, Mandic (private cloud), Zabbix, SolarWinds, Agile, Scrum, SDLC

Oct 2006 – Aug 2012 São Paulo/SP, Brazil

Software Developer | DIGISYSTEM

Duties

- Analyzed user requirements, and translated client needs into application design
- Design, code, and support software solutions that can easily be scaled depending on client needs
- Clients served as 3rd party: IBOPE, SESI/SENAI and NEXXYS

Achievements

- Reduced project costs by focusing on double-check requirements and create more accurate test processes with code review
- An excellent work at NEXXYS resulted in a job offer to join their team six months later

Sep 2004 – Jun 2006 Taquaritinga/SP,

Programmer | Politec

Duties

Brazil

Wrote code to specification in order to build two government-facing web-based applications

 Maintain product quality by carrying out reviews, performing continual tests, and analyzing feedback

Education

2008 – 2012 Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie

São Paulo/SP, Brazil B.S. Computer Science

Additional Skills & Interest

- Expert knowledge of .NET ecosystem such as C#, .NET, .NET Framework, and .NET Core
- Proficient in SQL Server, MySQL, and MongoDB databases
- Intermediate knowledge of microservices, containers with Docker and Kubernetes, and DevOps
- Proficient in Web environment development: HTML5, CSS3, XML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap,
 AngularJS, AJAX, JSON, REST and SOAP
- Extensive experience with design patterns, OOD, UML, testing (unit, integration, end-to-end),
 SOLID, teamwork, problem-solving and creative thinking